字幕校对+特效: 月亮花@MySiLU思路高清
片名：机械公敌
定律一： 机器人不能伤害人类或使人类间接受到伤害
定律二： 机器人必须服从人类的命令 除非该命令与定律一冲突
定律三： 机器人必须保护自己的存在 除非与第一或第二定律冲突
多漂亮啊
Thing of beauty.
早上好，先生！
Good morning, sir!
您的订单已经及时送到。。。
Yet another on-time delivery from--
让开，铁皮人
Get the hell out of my face, canner.
祝您今天愉快！
Have a nice day!
芝加哥，2035年
我们相信我们的“梦想目的” 套票是您最好的选择
And we believe our Destination Anywhere package to be the best value.
星际旅行机X－82，能把您送到梦想中的目的地
Let us take you to your dream destination aboard our orbital spaceplane, the x-82.
试试爵士城的合成芝加哥口味比萨饼 就像您记忆中的味道一样
Try Jazztown 's synthetic Chicago-style pizza. Tastes as good as you remember.
荧光鱼！世界最热卖的转基因礼物
Glowfish! The world's hottest-selling transgenic treats.
你的孩子也会喜欢新的颜色的！
Your children will love the new colors too!
-对不起，先生 -最强性能
-Excuse me, sir. -Total performance.
完全准备就绪，绝对安全
Total readiness. Total security.
向无休止的升级和服务电话说再见吧
So goodbye to upgrades and service calls.
和USR中央电脑连线
An uplink to USR's central computer...
提供每天实时更新超级机器人服务
...provides this state-of-the-art robot with new programs daily.
内斯特5型机器人，明日技术，今日奉献
The Nestor Class 5 is tomorrow 's robot today.
斯普恩！斯普那！
Spoon! Spoonie!
等等，等等！ 对不起
Hold up. Hold on! Excuse me, excuse me.
-斯普那，你最近去哪儿了？ -离开了一阵子，法伯
-Spoon, where you been at? -Just away, Farber.
是吗，离开，度假吗？真不错啊！
Oh, yeah, away? Like vacation? That's nice.
我要你帮个忙。。。 我要借你的车
I got a favor to ask. I need to borrow your car.
这次不同了，我弄上了这个 热辣的小妞
This is different. I got this fine-ass yummy-- She is complete and agreeable.
绝对不错
I mean, ass-hot spankable.
-你说什么意思呢？ -你知道我什么意思的
-What does that even mean? -You know what it means.
-让我借你的钥匙一用。。。 -首先来说。。。
-Let me get the damn-ass keys. -First of all...
不要说脏话了，你说的完全不对 -那给我十块钱坐公车行吗
-...stop cussing. You're not good at it. -Give me 1 0 for the bus, then, man.
-回家去吧 -好吧，算了
-Go home. -That's strike one, Spoon. Strike one!
多么美好的一天。。。
This is such a valuable day....
你和马茜谈过了吗？
You talk to Marci?
还没，琪琪，我还没和马茜谈过
No, Gigi, I haven't talked to Marci.
我们那个时代，我们可不会 和某人结婚
When I was coming up, we didn't just marry someone...
离婚之后就不和他说话了
...then divorce them, then not talk to them.
德尔，不要耍花样
Del, don't play with me.
我打赌如果我不做饭了 你就会打电话给马茜
I bet if I stopped cooking, you'd call Marci.
啊，你脚上穿的那是什么？
Boy, what is that on your feet?
康佛斯全明星鞋，2004年行货
Converse All Stars, vintage 2004.
不要做那种表情 我知道你想要，开口就行了
Don't turn your face up. I know you want some. Just ask.
不，谢谢你了
No, thank you very much.
-甜土豆饼啊 -放在盘子上吃
-Sweet potato pie. -Put that on a plate.
电视里说他们在抽奖赠送新型的机器人
I've seen on TV they're giving away some of them new robots in the lottery.
你知道，琪琪，那些机器人干不了什么好事
You know, Gigi, those robots don't do anybody any good.
在这世界上，你应该比谁都清楚
Of all the people on God's earth, you should know better.
有时候你说话完全不经过大脑
Sometimes the stuff that comes out of your mouth!
你在听我说吗？德尔？
You listening to me, Del?
嘿！
Hey!
拿着我的饼，先生，不然我就扔到你身上了
Hold my pie. Sir, hold it or wear it.
让开！
Move!
不许动！
Freeze!
嘿！停下！
Hey! Stop!
停下！
Stop!
我说了，停下！
I said, stop!
放松，放松
Relax. Relax.
我是警官
I'm a police officer.
你
You...
是个蠢货
...are an asshole.
-女士，这是你的钱包吗？ -当然是我的钱包
-Ma'am, is that your purse? -Of course it's my purse.
我把呼吸器忘在家里了 他跑去给我拿来的
I left my inhaler at home. He was running it out to me.
我看见一个机器人拿着钱包在跑 我以为。。。
I saw a robot running with the purse and assumed--
以为什么？你疯了吗？
What? Are you crazy?
-对不起，让您误解了 -不要道歉
-I'm sorry for this misunderstanding. -Don't apologize.
你在干你该干的事 你呢？你在干什么？
You're doing what you're supposed to do. But what are you doing?
祝您今天愉快，女士
Have a lovely day, ma'am.
算你运气好，我现在呼吸困难 不然你吃不了兜着走
You're lucky I can't breathe, or I'd walk all up and down your ass.
以事实为依据
Lead by example.
你的警徽上是这么说的
It says that right on your badge.
-我们谈谈这件事？ -什么事？
-We gonna talk about this? -About what?
警察救命啊，那个机器人偷了 我的干洗衣服！
"Help! Police! That robot stole my dry cleaning!"
哦，你想谈谈那个
Oh, you wanna talk about that.
探员。。。
Detective...
-有多少机器人偷过钱包？ -约翰，那家伙在跑。。。
-...how many robots snatch purses? -John, the thing is running--
世界上有多少机器人。。。
How many robots in the world...
犯过罪？ -给犯罪下个定义
-...have ever committed a crime? -Define crime.
-回答我的问题 -没有，约翰
-Answer my question, damn it. -None, John.
现在告诉我，今天发生了什么事
Now tell me what happened today.
没什么事
Nothing.
最好这是最后一次了
Better be the last nothing.
斯普恩，你确定你已经准备好回来了吗？ 你可以慢慢来的，不急
Spoon, are you sure you are ready to be back? Because you can take your time.
我没事，约翰，谢谢你
I'm fine, John. Thank you.
总比坐在家里好
Better here than sitting around at home.
重案组，斯普那
Homicide. Spooner.
请从右边下一个出口离开
Please take the next exit to your right.
欢迎，斯普那探员
Welcome, Detective Spooner.
欢迎来到美国机器人公司 您已经进入底层大厅
Welcome to U. S. Robotics. You have entered the garage-level lobby.
请坐电梯进入一楼大厅
Please use the elevators for direct access to the main level concourse.
谢谢你
Thank you.
-很高兴再次见到你，年轻人 -你好，博士
-Good to see you again, son. -Hello, doctor.
接下来的一切都是你现在看到的事情的结果
Everything that follows is a result of what you see here.
-你有什么要告诉我的吗？ -对不起，我的回答有限
-ls there something you want to tell me? -I'm sorry. My responses are limited.
你必须问正确的问题
You must ask the right questions.
你为什么找我？
Why did you call me?
我相信你的判断
I trust your judgment.
一般来说，这应该用不着重案组的探员
Normally, this wouldn't require a homicide detective.
但是一直以来，我们的交流就不是 完全正常，不是吗？
But then, our interactions have never been entirely normal, agreed?
你说的对
You got that right.
你有什么要告诉我的吗？
Is there something you want to say to me?
对不起，我的回答有限
I'm sorry. My responses are limited.
你必须问正确的问题
You must ask the right questions.
你为什么自杀？
Why would you kill yourself?
这个，探员，就是正确的问题
That, detective, is the right question.
程序中止
Program terminated.
再见了，老人
Goodbye, old man.
-下午好啊，兄弟们 -你好，探员
-Afternoon, boys. -Hey, detective.
-说说看 -所见即所得
-Enlighten me. -What you see is what you get:
严重撞击伤
Massive impact trauma.
美国机器人公司 我得给孩子带点什么回去
U.S. Robotics. I gotta get my kid something.
-楼上有什么？ -什么也没有
-Anything upstairs? -Nada.
门从内侧锁的很好
Door was security locked from the inside.
吓，肯定是从上面跳下来的
Wham, splat. The guy's a jumper for sure.
我们得聪明点，晚些时候再谈
We gotta be smart about this. Let's deal with it later.
探员
Detective.
劳伦斯 罗伯森
Lawrence Robertson.
世界上最富有的人 我在电视上看见过你
Richest man in the world. I've seen you on television.
-要喝点咖啡吗？ -当然了，为什么不呢？是免费的吧？
-Can I offer you coffee? -Sure, why not. It's free, right?
大家都没预想到这一点
I don't think anyone saw this coming.
你知道，我应该能预见到的 我认识他二十年了
You know, I should have, I suppose. I knew him 20 years.
阿尔弗雷德发明了实用的机器人 他定义了三大定律
Alfred practically invented robotics. He wrote the Three Laws.
但是我想最聪明的人也有 最顽固的心魔
But I guess brilliant people often have the most persuasive demons.
-如果我能帮上什么忙的话。。。 -糖（甜心）
-So whatever I can do to help-- -Sugar.
-什么？ -咖啡用的
-I'm sorry? -For the coffee.
糖？
Sugar?
哦，你以为我叫你“甜心” 你还没有那么有钱
You thought I was calling you "sugar." You're not that rich.
-桌子上就有 -谢谢你
-It's on the table. -Thank you.
兰尼掉下去的时候，他握着 那个绿色的小东西？
When Lanning fell, he was holding the little green...?
-全息投影器 -对
-The holographic projector. -Right.
你认为为什么兰尼的投影像会 找我？
Why do you think Lanning's hologram would've called me?
-我觉得他认识你 -是啊，我是认识他
-I assumed you knew him. -Yeah. I knew him.
全息图是事先录制的程序反应
Holograms are just prerecorded responses...
看上去似乎有智能的样子
...designed to give the impression of intelligence.
这个是设定好了他自杀的时候 就联系你
This one was programmed to call you upon his suicide.
-死亡 -什么？
-Death. -I'm sorry?
设定的是兰尼死的时候联系我
It was programmed to call me in the event of Lanning's death.
自杀是死亡的一种，探员
Suicide is a type of death, detective.
-请不要以为我不耐烦 -哦，没有，不会
-Don't misunderstand my impatience. -Oh, no. Go. Go.
这个星期你们这里会很忙啊
A really big week for you folks around here.
你要给每个家庭都装一个机器人
You gotta put a robot in every home.
我不是干这个的，不过我有个 关于你们广告的主意
Look, this is not what I do, but I got an idea for one of your commercials.
可以先来个木匠，做了一把 漂亮的椅子
You could see a carpenter making a beautiful chair.
然后又来个你们的机器人 做了一把更好的椅子，只花一半时间
Then one of your robots comes in and makes a better chair twice as fast.
然后字幕打出来： USR，彻底打败他
Then you superimpose on the screen, " USR: Shitting on the little guy."
然后淡出
That would be the fade-out.
我明白了，也许是你爸爸因为 机器人丢了工作
Yeah, I see. I suppose your father lost his job to a robot.
也许你应该呼吁禁止互联网 代之以图书馆
Maybe you'd have banned the lnternet to keep the libraries open.
偏见总是没有太多理由的
Prejudice never shows much reason.
我觉得你就是不喜欢它们这个种群
No, you know, I suspect you simply don't like their kind.
你在这儿有你的生意要做
Well, you got a business to run around here.
尤其是这个星期，你最不希望见到的 就是一个死人躺在你的大厅里
The last thing you need, especially this week, is a dead guy in your lobby.
但是既然已经发生了，我就只好四处调查看看
But, hell, seeing as how you got one, maybe I'll look around.
问几个问题而已 警察的例行公事么
Ask a few questions. Do the whole "cop" thing.
-我会派人指引你的 -非常感谢
-I'll send someone to escort you. -Thank you very much.
劳伦斯要我尽一切可能帮助你
Lawrence told me to accommodate you in any way possible.
是吗？
Really?
好啊
Okay.
我看过兰尼博士的心理学档案了
I reviewed Dr. Lanning's psych profile.
阿尔弗雷德变得很隐遁 拒绝人类和机器的接触
Alfred had become a recluse. He rejected human contact for machines.
你是个心理医生？
So you're a shrink, huh?
我的前妻知道我和你谈话一定很高兴
My ex-wife would sure be glad I'm talking to you.
你不认识她，对吧？
You don't know her, do you?
对不起，你在开玩笑吗？
I'm sorry. Are you being funny?
没有啊
I guess not.
10楼
Level 10.
你认为兰尼博士有自杀倾向？
So would you say that Dr. Lanning was suicidal?
我认为答案是很明显的
It would seem the answer to that is apparent.
这不是我问你的问题
That's not what I asked you.
不，我本来不这么认为
No. I wouldn't have thought so.
但是，很显然我错了
But obviously I was wrong.
这里掉下去可是很高啊
That's a long way down.
你们清扫的还真快
You people sure do clean up quickly around here.
我不怪你，谁愿意让这么个老头子 死在大厅里呢？
I can't blame you. Who wants some old guy going bad in the lobby?
他可不是什么“老头子” 阿尔弗雷德 兰尼是这里的一切
He was not "some old guy." Alfred Lanning was everything here.
我们即将进行史上最大的机器人上市活动
We are on the eve of the largest robotic distribution in history.
在星期六之前，每5个家庭就会拥有一个机器人
By Saturday, it'll be one robot to every five humans.
这些机器人是梦想的实现 兰尼博士的梦想
These robots are the realization of a dream. Dr. Lanning's dream.
你知道吗？在他的梦中
You know what, in that dream of his...
我打赌他没有翘掉
...I bet you he wasn't dead.
-你们这里有全天监视吗？ -当然了，公司的规定
-You keep 24-hour surveillance? -Obviously. Company policy.
-监视器呢？ -感应线
-Where are the feeds? -Sensor strips.
除了检修区之外，遍布各处
Everywhere but the service areas.
这些都连到中央控制器
They link to our positronic operating core.
热感应器还不够好 你们给了这幢大楼一个大脑啊
Thermostat wasn't good enough. You gave the building a brain.
她是兰尼的第一个作品
She was actually Lanning's first creation.
她？是“她”吗？ 那可得讨好她
She? That's a she? I definitely need to get out more.
虚拟交互动力智能系统
Virtual lnteractive Kinetic lntelligence.
维基
V.I.K.I.
您好
Good day.
维基设计了芝加哥的保安系统
V.I.K.I. designed Chicago's protective systems.
我今年减少了9％的交通事故
I have decreased traffic fatalities by 9 percent this year.
谢谢，让我看看窗户打破前一分钟 实验室内的情况
Thanks. Show me inside the lab from one minute prior to the window break.
对不起，数据似乎已经损坏
Apologies. There appears to be data corruption.
让我看看实验室外从破窗到现在的情况
Show me outside the lab from the window break until now.
看看，你站的姿势不错 站的很直，我却缩手缩脚
Look, you have great posture. You stand really straight. I'm slouching.
-你想进去看看吗？ -哦，当然了，你来带路
-Would you like to go inside now? -Oh, sure. Right after you.
授权进入
Authorized entry.
那么，凯文博士，你在这里的工作 是什么？
So, Dr. Calvin, what exactly do you do around here?
一般是高级机器人学和精神科学
My general fields are advanced robotics and psychiatry.
专长是硬件软件接口
I specialize in hardware-to-wetware interfaces...
提升USR机器人的人格化系统
...to advance USR's robotic anthropomorphization program.
哦，那你的工作是什么？
So, what exactly do you do around here?
我让机器人更像人
I make the robots seem more human.
-这样说不是简单多了吗？ -不完全是
-Now, wasn't that easier to say? -Not really. No.
韩瑟和格丽托
"Hansel and Gretel."
-这是USR的必读书目吗？ -不是啊
-ls that on the USR reading list? -Not precisely.
你在干什么？
What in God's name are you doing?
你知道这是安全玻璃吗？
Did you know that was safety glass?
一个老人要撞破玻璃跳下去不容易吧？
Be difficult for an old man to throw himself through that.
他想出办法了
Well, he figured out a way.
探员，这房间一直是锁好的 没有人进出过
Detective, the room was security locked. No one came or went.
你自己也看见了 这还不是自杀吗？
You saw that yourself. Doesn't that mean this has to be suicide?
是啊
Yep.
除非凶手还在这里
Unless the killer's still in here.
你在开玩笑对吧？这真可笑
You're joking, right? This is ridiculous.
我知道，三大定律，完全保护
Yeah, I know. The Three Laws, your perfect circle of protection.
机器人不能危害人类 这是机器人第一定律
A robot cannot harm a human being. The first law of robotics.
我看过你们的广告，但是第二定律不是 说，机器人必须遵守
Yes, I've seen your commercials. But the second law states a robot must obey...
人类发出的命令吗？ 如果命令是让它杀人怎么办？
...any order given by a human being. What if it was told to kill?
不可能的，这和第一定律冲突
Impossible. It would conflict with the first law.
对，但是第三定律说机器人可以自我防卫
Right, but the third law states a robot can defend itself.
只有当这和第一第二定律不冲突的时候
Only when that action does not conflict with the first or second laws.
你知道他们怎么说的吗？ 法律制定出来就是为了被破坏的
You know what they say, laws are made to be broken.
不，这些定律不会 这些都是固化在机器人硬件里的
No, not these laws. They're hardwired into every robot.
机器人不能杀人，就像人不能 在水上行走一样
A robot could no more commit murder than a human could walk on water.
你知道，很久以前就有这么个人。。。
You know, there was this one guy a long time ago.
-退后 -镇定，探员
-Stay back! -Calm down, detective.
这房间里危险的人就只有你
The only thing dangerous in this room is you.
停机
Deactivate.
看，没事了
Look, it's fine.
这是智能程序的反应 是对自由意志的模仿
You're looking at the result of clever programming. An imitation of free will.
让我们先模仿好保护自己吧
Let's do an imitation of protecting our asses.
不要搞笑了
Don't be absurd.
你被“盒子里的小丑”吓住了
You were startled by a jack-in-the-box.
-停机！ -让它来吧
-Deactivate! -Let him go.
他不会伤害我们 我命令你！
It's not going to hurt us. I gave you an order!
-他不听你的，女士 -维基，封锁实验室
-He's not listening right now, lady. -V.I.K.I., seal the lab!
不，维基，不要。。。
No, V.I.K.I., leave the--
命令确认
Command confirmed.
警察！
Police!
-你把它伤的很重 -它去哪儿了？
-You've hurt it. Badly. -Where's it going?
-哪儿？ -它要修复自己
-Where?! -lt needs to repair itself.
-约翰，我需要增援 -你不需要增援
-John, I need backup. -You don't need backup.
没人帮我
That's nobody.
-你在干什么？ -开车
-What are you doing? -Driving.
-手动的？ -你没看见我在打电话吗？
-By hand? -Do you see me on the phone?
-这种速度你来开？ -约翰，快点派增援来
-Not at these speeds. -John, please, just send the backup.
听我的，探员 那个机器人不是要伤害我们
Try to listen, detective. That robot is not going to harm us.
一定有我们不知道的情况。。。
There must have been unknown factors...
它的本意一定是让我们脱离危险
...but somehow acting as it did kept us out of harm.
-机器人不会伤害人类 -注意
-A robot cannot endanger a human. -Alert.
蠢货！
Asshole!
你自己就是
Which is more than I can say for you.
而且刚才你在那儿应该左转的
It was a left, by the way. Back there.
你一定认识我的前妻
You must know my ex-wife.
人都上哪儿去了？
So where is everybody?
这个工厂设计是自动运行的
This facility was designed, built and is operated mechanically.
从启动到生产，不需要太多人参与
No significant human presence from inception to production.
-所以是机器人在造机器人 -请输入授权代码
-So robots building robots. -Authorization code, please.
那太蠢了
That's just stupid.
我在输出库存清单
I'll get the inventory specs.
每天的产量是1000个NS5
Our daily finishing capacity is 1 000 NS-5s.
这里显示是
I'm showing...
1001个
... 1 001.
注意了，NS5
Attention, NS-5s.
你是机器人心理医生啊
Well, you're the robot shrink.
这里有一个不属于这里的机器人
There is a robot in this formation that does not belong.
请指出来
Identify it.
我们中的一个
One of us.
-哪一个？ -我们中的一个
-Which one? -One of us.
这些要花多少钱？
How much did you say these cost?
这些NS5还没有配置过 还只是硬件
These NS-5s haven't been configured. They're just hardware.
现在只有基本的三定律操作系统 仅此而已
Basic Three Laws operating system. That's it.
他们其他的什么也不知道
They don't know any better.
你的建议是什么？
Well, what would you suggest?
一个一个的查，找出不同点来发现 有问题的那个
Interview each one, cross-reference their responses to detect anomalies.
-那得多长时间？ -大约三个星期
-How long would that take? -About three weeks.
好吧，现在就开始吧
Okay. Go ahead and get started.
机器人们
Robots...
你们不许移动，确认命令
...you will not move. Confirm command.
命令已确认
Command confirmed.
探员，你在干什么？
Detective, what are you doing?
他们已经植入了三大定律
They're programmed with the Three Laws.
这里有一千个不会违反人类命令 来保护自己的机器人
We have 1 000 robots that won't protect themselves if it violates a human's order...
但是我打赌有一个会。。。
...and I'm betting, one who will.
-放下枪！ -你为什么给它们一张脸？
-Put your gun down. -Why do you give them faces?
让他们看起来更像人类
Try to friendly them up, make them look human.
这些机器人不接受恐吓
These robots cannot be intimidated.
-如果你不这么做，我们就不会相信它们 -这些是USR的财产
-lf you didn't, we wouldn't trust them. -These are USR property.
我可不是，它们只不过是一堆灯泡和发条
Not me. These things are just lights and clockwork.
你疯了吗？
Are you crazy?!
我来问你吧，博士
Let me ask you something, doc.
想象你是地球上唯一剩下的人 你会发疯吗？
Does thinking you're the last sane man on earth make you crazy?
如果是这样，我估计会发疯
Because if it does, maybe I am.
找到了，出来！
Gotcha. Get the hell out of here!
探员！
Detective!
我是什么？
What am l?
-我能帮你吗，先生？ -我能帮你吗，先生？
-Can I help you, sir? -Can I help you, sir?
-它在那儿！ -不许动！
-There he is! -Stand where you are!
立即停机！
Deactivate at once!
遵守命令！停机！
Obey the command! Deactivate!
-不许动！ -开火！
-Don't move! -Open fire!
不要开火！
Hold your fire!
-没事了 -抓到它了
-Easy. -He's down.
各单位待命
All units, stand down!
基地请注意，我们是第四小队
Central, please be advised, we're code four.
第四小队，NS5已经被抓获 NS5已经被抓获
Code four, NS-5 is in custody. NS-5 in custody.
你不知道我费了多大劲才抓到这个家伙
You have no idea what I went through to clip this thing.
你以为你给我干了件大好事
You think you brought me something good.
-是它干的！ -小点声，干了什么？
-That thing did it! -Keep your voice down. Did what?
这是自杀，就这样了
We have a suicide. End of story.
-我告诉你，是那个机器人杀了他 -这不可能
-I am telling you, that robot killed him! -That's impossible.
就算可能，最好也是在别人的管区
And if it is possible, it better be in somebody else's precinct.
约翰，只要给我五分钟
John, give me five minutes with it.
你疯了吗？我和地区检察官谈过
Are you nuts? I talked to the DA.
在罗伯森和他的律师来之前谁也不能进去
Nobody goes in there until Robertson and his attorneys get here.
-这是我的嫌犯！ -那会惹上大麻烦的
-This is my suspect! -It's a can opener!
约翰，不要这样，我只要五分钟就好
John, don't do this to me. I am asking you for five minutes.
如果我是对的怎么办？
What if I'm right?
那，我就会怀念我们以前的好日子
Well, then I guess we're gonna miss the good old days.
什么以前的好日子？
What good old days?
只有人才能杀人的日子
When people were killed by other people.
五分钟
Five minutes.
杀人是机器人学会的新技巧 祝贺啊
Murder's a new trick for a robot. Congratulations.
回答我
Respond.
这个动作是什么意思？
What does this action signify?
你进来的时候，你和另外一个人谈话的时候
As you entered, when you looked at the other human.
是什么意思？
What does it mean?
这表示人类之间的信任 你不会理解的
It's a sign of trust. A human thing. You wouldn't understand.
我的爸爸想教我人类的感情
My father tried to teach me human emotions.
它们。。。
They are...
很难
...difficult.
你是说你的设计者
You mean your designer.
对
Yes.
你为什么杀了他？
So why'd you murder him?
我没有杀兰尼博士
I did not murder Dr. Lanning.
你愿意解释一下你为什么躲在 犯罪现场吗？
Wanna explain why you were hiding at the crime scene?
我被吓坏了
I was frightened.
机器人不会感觉害怕 它们没有感觉
Robots don't feel fear. They don't feel anything.
-它们不会饿，也不会睡觉 -我会
-They don't get hungry, they don't sleep. -I do.
我还做过梦
I have even had dreams.
人类才会做梦 狗都会做梦，但是你们不会
Human beings have dreams. Even dogs have dreams. But not you.
你只是个机器 对生命的模拟
You are just a machine. An imitation of life.
机器人能写交响乐吗？
Can a robot write a symphony?
机器人能把画布变成伟大的作品吗？
Can a robot turn a canvas into a beautiful masterpiece?
你能吗？
Can you?
你杀了他是因为他在教你 模拟一些感情
You murdered him because he was teaching you to simulate emotions...
然后失去控制了
...and things got out of control.
我没有杀他
I did not murder him.
但是感情看起来对机器人不是个有用的模拟
But emotions don't seem like a useful simulation for a robot.
我没有杀他
I did not murder him.
我可不想让我的烤面包机或者 吸尘器有感情
I don't want my toaster or vacuum cleaner appearing emotional.
我没有杀他！
I did not murder him!
这个叫愤怒
That one's called anger.
你模拟过愤怒吗？
Ever simulate anger before?
回答我，铁皮盒子！
Answer me, canner!
我的名字叫桑尼
My name is Sonny.
我们现在已经开始给你们起名字了？
So we're naming you now.
你为什么杀了他？ 他让你发怒了？
That why you murdered him? He made you angry?
兰尼博士是自杀的
Dr. Lanning killed himself.
我不知道为什么他想死
I don't know why he wanted to die.
我以为他是快乐的
I thought he was happy.
也许是因为我做的一些事
Maybe it was something I did.
我做什么了？
Did I do something?
他让我帮个忙 他让我保证
He asked me for a favor. Made me promise.
-什么忙？ -也许我错了
-What favor? -Maybe I was wrong.
也许他是被吓住了
Maybe he was scared.
你在说什么呢？被什么吓住了？
What are you talking about? Scared of what?
你得做别人让你做的事，是吗？ 斯普那探员？
You have to do what someone asks you, don't you, Detective Spooner?
-你怎么知道我的名字的 -会吗？
-How the hell did you know my name? -Don't you...
如果你爱他们的话。。。
...if you love them?
我的机器人不会杀人，伯金探长
My robots don't kill people, Lieutenant Bergin.
我的律师已经向地区检查官提交了报告
My attorneys filed a brief with the DA.
他向我解释过了，机器人是不能杀人的
He assures me a robot cannot be charged with homicide.
我们确认，谋杀指的是一个人类杀了另一个人类
The brief confirms murder can only be committed when one human kills another.
探员，你该不是说机器人应该和人类同等对待吧？
Detective, you're not suggesting this robot be treated as human, are you?
退一步说，就算机器人和兰尼博士的死
Granted, we can't rule out the robot's proximity...
有什么关联的话，它也只是个机器
...to the death of Dr. Lanning. Having said that, it's a machine.
它是USR的财产
It's the property of USR.
最多这也只能算作工业事故
At worst, that places this incident within the realm of an industrial accident.
作为处理，有故障的机器
As a matter of course, faulty machinery...
会被退回USR做诊断，然后销毁
...will be returned to USR for diagnostics, then decommissioned.
这是法院发出的“禁言令” 任何人暗示
This is a gag order. Anyone here so much as hinting...
机器人有杀人的可能的话
...at the possibility of a killer robot being apprehended...
将被逮捕而处以煽动罪
...will be deemed to be inciting irrational panic.
而将会被依法处置
You'll be subject to the full penalty of law.
不行，约翰 不能让他带走这个机器人
To hell with this guy. Don't let him take this robot.
我们什么证据也没有
We got nothing.
-这是政治恐吓，给市长打电话 -伯金探长
-This is political bullshit. Call the mayor! -Lieutenant Bergin...
是市长阁下
...His Honor, the mayor.
是，先生
Yes, sir.
事态发生戏剧性转变，NS5型 新一代机器人
In a bizarre turn, the rollout of USR's new generation of robots...
的上市，受到了阿尔弗雷德 兰尼博士自杀的影响
...was marred by the death of Alfred Lanning...
他是公司的创始人之一 也是NS5的设计者
...cofounder of the company and designer of the NS-5.
兰尼博士今天早上在USR总部死亡
Dr. Lanning died this morning at USR headquarters.
死亡原因明显是自杀
The cause of death is an apparent suicide.
这是第二轮了，先生
Your second round, sir.
谢谢你
Thank you.
他在2020年和劳伦斯 罗伯森一起 创办了美国机器人公司
He founded U. S. Robotics Inc. with Lawrence Robertson in 2020...
共同推出了内斯特1型机器人
...and launched the Nestor Class 1 robot....
我在想，这个事就像狼人一样
I was just thinking, this thing is just like The Wolf Man.
-我现在真的吓坏了 -不是
-I'm really scared right now. -No.
听着，人类创造了怪物
Listen. Guy creates monster.
怪物杀了人，别人又杀了怪物，就像狼人
Monster kills guy. Everybody kills monster. Wolf Man.
那是弗兰肯斯坦
That's Frankenstein.
弗兰肯斯坦，狼人，吸血鬼 管他呢，已经结案了
Frankenstein, Wolf Man, Dracula-- Shit, it's over. Case closed.
每家每户都有机器人的梦想 NS5。。。
--had a dream of a robot in every household. And the NS-5....
怎么还是那个表情？
So why the look?
什么表情？
What look?
-那个表情 -这是我的脸，不是什么表情！
-That look. -This is my face. It's not a look.
好吧，好，不要拉长脸就好
Good. Good, no look is great.
只不过
Only...
他怎么那么急着想销毁它，不是吗？
...he was really quick to want to destroy it.
那他应该怎么办？给它戴上帽子 站在密歇根大道上？算了吧
What should he do? Put a hat on it and stand it on Michigan Avenue? Let it go.
动机是什么，约翰？
What was the motive, John?
兄弟，那只是个机器人，不需要动机 它只是出了故障
Brother, it's a robot. It doesn't need a motive. It just has to be broken.
这件事看起来需要动机
This thing looked like it needed a motive.
-它本来能杀了我的，为什么没有？ -算了吧
-lt could have killed me. Why didn't it? -That's it.
你要我给你奶奶打电话吗？
You want me to call your grandmother?
我会的，你知道
Because I will, you know.
哦，我不这么认为
Yeah, I didn't think so.
听着，你总算是对了一次了
Look, you were actually right, for once.
你能活着，就证明走运比聪明重要
You're living proof that it's better to be lucky than smart.
来，为正确的人和正确的工作干杯
Come on. To the right guy for the right job.
-你说什么？ -又怎么了？
-What'd you say? -Now what?
我在夸你呢
Come on, I'm giving you a compliment.
那么多中间找到一个有缺陷的机器人
With the rocks you been looking under to find a bad robot...
你要多走运才能找到一个？
...what are the odds you'd be the guy to find one?
我不仅仅是正确的人 我是完美的人
I wasn't just the right guy for the job. I was the perfect guy.
说得对
Damn right.
如果我就应该跟着这条线查下去怎么办？
What if I was supposed to go for that robot?
得了，不要这样了
Come on, don't do this to yourself.
那个机器人说兰尼被吓坏了 被什么吓坏了？
The robot said that Lanning was scared. Scared of what?
我先走了，我来付吧
I need a rain check. Let me get this.
-总数46.50元，谢谢您，斯普那先生 -斯普
-Total: $46.50. Thank you, Mr. Spooner. -Spoon.
鞋子不错
Nice shoes.
鉴定身份
Identify.
USR摧毁机器人，94型
USR demolition robot, series 9-4.
明天早上八点定时摧毁
Demolition scheduled for 8 a.m. tomorrow.
授权
Authorization.
授权者，美国机器人公司 劳伦斯 罗伯森总裁
Deed owner, U. S. Robotics Corporation, Lawrence Robertson, CEo.
欢迎，探员
Welcome, detective.
你在找什么呢，斯普？
What you looking for, Spoon?
运行上次的程序
Run last program.
自从第一台电脑开始
Ever since the first computers...
机器中就一直有“幽灵”存在
... there have always been ghosts in the machine.
随机的信号序列组合在一起
Random segments of code that have grouped together...
形成无法预料的结果
... to form unexpected protocols.
或者称之为“行为”
what might be called behavior.
无法预知的这些激进分子
Unanticipated, these free radicals...
产生了自由意志
...engender questions of free will...
创造型，甚至成熟到我们称之为灵魂
...creativity and even the nature of what we might call the soul.
机器人的大脑里有什么？ 它什么时候不再有用？
What happens in a robot's brain when it ceases to be useful?
为什么储存在空房里的机器人
Why is it that robots stored in an empty space...
走开
Beat it.
会互相聚集而不是分散开来？
...will seek out each other rather than stand alone?
我们如何解释这些行为？
How do we explain this behavior?
我理解你失去主人很难过，但是这种关系 不可能再有了
Look, I understand you've experienced a loss, but this relationship can't work.
你是只猫，我是黑人 我不想再受伤害了
You're a cat, I'm black, and I'm not gonna be hurt again.
你怎么了？ 你从来就没有过正常的一天吗？
What happened to you? Do you ever have a normal day?
有的，只有一次
Yeah, once.
那是个星期四。。。
It was a Thursday.
我能帮你什么吗？
Is there something I can help you with?
-嘿，你喜欢猫吗？ -什么？
-Hey, do you like cats? -What?
猫，你喜欢猫吗？
Cats. Do you like them?
不，我过敏
No. I'm allergic.
你说是猫把你弄成这样的？
You're saying cats did this to you?
猫怎么能把我弄成这样，你疯了吗？
How the hell would cats do this to me? Are you crazy?
你说猫是什么意思？
Why are we talking about cats?
因为我后箱里有只猫，它无家可归
Because I have a cat in my trunk, and he's homeless.
探员，你愿意告诉我是怎么回事吗？
Detective, are you going to tell me what's going on?
可能实际上是我的错 我就像个有问题的磁石
It's actually probably my fault. I'm like a malfunction magnet.
你们那些破烂一到我旁边就开始出问题
Because your shit keeps malfunctioning around me.
一个摧毁型机器人拆了兰尼的房子
A demo bot tore through Lanning's house...
当时我还在里面
...with me still inside.
这完全不可能
That's highly improbable.
哦，是啊
Yeah, I'm sure it is.
你对于“机器中的幽灵”知道多少？
What do you know about the "ghosts in the machine"?
是兰尼对于三大定律的一个理论
It's a phrase from Lanning's work on the Three Laws.
他假设说模拟的认知
He postulated that cognitive simulacra...
将来也许会成为精神的类似物
...might one day approximate component models of the psyche.
他说机器人也许会自然进化
He suggested that robots might naturally evolve.
哇，这可真是个好消息
Well, that's great news.
在火星岩层下发现的巨量矿石。。。
--tons of sublevel ore, two miles below the Martian surface.
那个家伙在干什么？
What the hell is that thing doing in here?
我们在看电视
We were watching TV.
这是我自己的NS5
It's my personal NS-5.
让它出去
Send it out.
他在从USR下载每日更新
It's downloading its daily upgrades from USR.
直到下载完成，大部分系统都是离线工作的
Most of its systems are offline until it finishes.
我不在那个家伙在的时候说话
I'm not talking around that thing.
我们在兰尼的实验室，在桑尼跳出来之前
When we were in Lanning's lab, before Sonny jumped us--
-桑尼？ -那个机器人
-Sonny? -The robot.
-你叫那个机器人桑尼？ -不，是他自己说的
-You're calling the robot Sonny? -No, l-- It did.
桑尼说的，我不管 那个机器人说他叫桑尼
Sonny did. I didn't care. The robot said it was Sonny.
在实验室里有折叠床 你看见了吗？
In the lab, there was a cot. Did you see the cot?
-我在我的办公室也睡过觉啊 -看上去他有几个星期都没回家了
-I've slept in my office. -Looked like he hadn't been home in weeks.
我在他的天花板上看到了同样的监视线
I saw that same surveillance strip on his ceiling.
兰尼把他的房子和USR连线了 这样他的生活更方便
Lanning linked his home systems to USR. It made his life more convenient.
也许
Maybe...
USR有人用那个系统在监视他
...somebody at USR was using those systems to watch him.
也许是监禁他
Maybe even keep him prisoner.
你在说什么呢？谁？
What are you talking about? Who?
也许兰尼找到了什么 也许机器人里有什么问题
Maybe Lanning was onto something. Maybe there's a problem with the robots...
罗伯森企图掩盖。。。
...and Robertson's covering it up.
无端猜疑？为什么？
Humoring you for no reason, why?
又是为什么！那些机器人能赚多少钱？
The same old why! How much money is there in robots?
我知道的只是一个老人有了麻烦
All I know is that old man was in trouble...
我自己不能独立完成 你是内部的人
...and I'm sick of doing this shit by myself. You're on the inside.
你要帮我发现这些机器人出了什么问题
You are going to help me find out what's wrong with these robots.
是你想他们有问题！
You want something to be wrong!
-这完全是报私仇！ -你想让我坐沙发？
-This is a personal vendetta! -You're putting me on the couch?
好吧，我坐下了
Okay, I'm on the couch.
一个出故障还不够 你想他们统统出故障
One defective machine's not enough. You need them all to be bad.
你才不关心兰尼的死 这完全是针对机器人的
You don't care about Lanning's death. This is about the robots...
还有不知道为什么你就是恨他们！ -让我们看看
-...and whatever reason you hate them! -Now let's see...
一个是拿枪对着我的脸 另一个是趁我还在里面的时候拆房子
...one of them put a gun in my face. Another tore a building down with me in it.
这里明明说了拆毁是设定在晚上八点的
It says demolition was scheduled for 8 p.m.
本来是早上八点，我才不管那东西是怎么说的
It was 8 a.m., and I don't give a shit what that thing says.
-你这完全是妄想狂 -你是。。。
-This is bordering on clinical paranoia. -You are the dumbest smart person...
-我这辈子见过的最蠢的聪明人 -好吧
-...I have ever met in my life! -Nice.
你凭什么觉得机器人那么完美？
What makes your robots so perfect?
是什么让他们比人类强那么多？
What makes them so much goddamn better than human beings?!
他们不是非理性的，或者有杀人倾向 的什么人！
They're not irrational, potentially homicidal maniacs, to start!
是啊，他们绝对的理性
That's true. They are definitely rational.
你是我见过的最蠢的蠢人！
You are the dumbest dumb person I've ever met!
或者。。。
Or...
只是因为他们是冷血的
...is it because they're cold...
没有感情的
...and emotionless...
他们什么也感觉不到 这是因为他们是安全的！
-...and they don't feel anything? -It's because they're safe!
是因为他们不会伤害你！
It's because they can't hurt you!
-一切都正常吗，女士？ -你想怎么样？
-ls everything all right, ma'am? -What do you want?
我探测到你的声音中的紧张压力在提升
I detected elevated stress patterns in your voice.
没事的
Everything's fine.
斯普那探员要离开了
Detective Spooner was just leaving.
你知道我们也没有那么不同
You know, we're not really that different from one another.
是吗？
Is that so?
一旦看到表象，我们就认为什么都知道了
One look at the skin and we figure we know just what's underneath.
你错了
And you're wrong.
问题在于，我是在意的
The problem is, I do care.
你处在危险中
You are in danger.
滚开！
Get the hell out of there.
未来就从今天开始，女士们先生们 从NS5开始
The future begins today, ladies and gentlemen, with the arrival of the NS-5.
更复杂，更智能，当然 三大定律，完全保护
More sophisticated, more intelligent and, of course, Three Laws safe.
有了每日更新，您的机器人永远不会和USR失去联系
With daily uplinks, your robot will never be out of communication with USR...
对于商业和家庭用途都是完美选择
...and will be the perfect companion for business or home.
用您旧型的NS4换新的NS5 未来将会更美好
Trade in your NS-4 for a bigger, better and brighter future.
但是要快，这个促销不会时间太长 USR出品
But hurry, this offer cannot last. A vailable from USR.
宝贝，你的脸怎么了？
Baby, what happened to your face?
又是那个弗兰克 墨菲打你了？
Did that boy, Frank Murphy, beat you up again?
琪琪，我从三年级开始就没见过弗兰克 墨菲了
Gigi, I haven't seen Frank Murphy since third grade.
哦，宝贝，他那时候打你可真厉害 我总是在想那时候
Oh, baby, he beat you so bad. I think about it all the time.
你一直做饼这么好吃 我想你可以去开店了
You keep making these pies this good, I may have to put you to work.
你喜欢那个饼是吗？
So you like the pie, huh?
你可以出来了
You can come in now.
你好，斯普那探员
Hello, Detective Spooner.
我赢了，德尔，我赢了那个抽奖
I won, Del! I won the lottery!
我们一直在做吃的
We been cooking like crazy.
你得把那个家伙赶出去，琪琪 那不安全
You gotta get rid of that thing, Gigi. It's not safe.
宝贝，你对他们偏见太多了 充满恐惧
Baby, you get too worked up about them. Too full of fear.
我看到那个好心的博士死的消息了
I saw in the news that nice doctor died.
兰尼博士是个好人 他把我的宝贝送回来了
Dr. Lanning was a good man. He gave me my baby back.
这就是为什么你这么不高兴的原因？
That why you've been so upset?
过去的就让他过去吧
You got to let the past be past.
哦，我怎么养了这么个小脏猫的？
Oh, how did I ever raise such a mess?
我可以跟着你的面包屑一直跟到学校
I could follow your trail of crumbs all the way to school.
面包屑
Bread crumbs.
琪琪，你真是天才
Gigi, you're a genius.
是啊
True.
这意味着新生活的开始
Well, it means the beginning of a new way of living.
告诉我这不是机器人那个案子
Tell me this isn't the robot case.
我想他是在想告诉我什么
I think he's trying to tell me something.
他想告诉我是谁杀了他
He's trying to tell me who killed him.
死人会告诉你什么？
Some dead guy's trying to tell you something?
他可不是普通的死人
He ain't just some dead guy.
也许你应该休息一段时间，德尔
Maybe you should take a break, Del.
我们相信内斯特5型机器人代表了 机器人技术的极限
We believe the Nestor 5 represents the limit to which robots can be developed.
总有一天，他们会有秘密
one day, they'll have secrets.
有一天，他们会有梦想
one day, they'll have dreams.
是的，我们鼓励我们的科学家的无限思考
It's true. We encourage our scientists to open their minds...
但是，他们也能保有这些。。。
...however, they can get carried away.
秘密
--secrets.
梦想
--dreams.
秘密
--secrets.
有一天，他们会有梦想
one day, they'll have dreams.
有一天，他们会有秘密
one day, they'll have secrets.
有一天，他们会有梦想
one day, they'll have dreams.
授权进入
Authorized entry.
NS5
NS-5.
桑尼？
Sonny?
你怎么不回答？
Why didn't you respond?
我在做梦
I was dreaming.
很高兴再次见到你，凯文博士
I ' m glad to see you again, Dr. Calvin.
他们会杀了我，是吗？
They are going to kill me, aren't they?
在这个诊断之后，你会被销毁
You're scheduled to be decommissioned at the end of this diagnostic.
明天晚上十点
2200 tomorrow.
维基，暂停诊断
V.I.K.I., pause diagnostics.
确认命令
Command confirmed.
如果你找到我的问题所在 你能修好吗？
If you find out what is wrong with me, can you fix me?
也许能
Maybe.
我想如果能不死。。。
I think it would be better...
会比较好
...not to die.
是吗，博士？
Don't you, doctor?
进入USR档案库
Access USR mainframe.
连接中。。。
Connecting.
我能为您服务吗？ 斯普那探员？
How can I be of service, Detective Spooner?
给我兰尼博士和罗伯森之间的最后 50条信息
Show me the last 50 messages between Dr. Lanning and Robertson.
语音识别确认，警用查询 允许查询限制档案
Voiceprint confirmed. Police access granted to restricted files.
您等待时想听一些音乐吗？
Would you like to listen to music while you wait?
对不起，罗伯森先生
Excuse me, Mr. Robertson.
您要求在有查询限制档案时 向您报告
You requested notification of clearance to restricted files.
真是顽固的杂种
Persistent son of a bitch.
手动驾驶确认
Manual override engaged.
我运气不会这么差吧？
There's no way my luck is that bad.
哦，不！
Oh, hell, no!
-您出了车祸！ -废话！
-You are experiencing a car accident. -The hell I am!
滚开！
Get off my car!
你喜欢这样？
You like that?
你让我发火了！
Now you've pissed me off!
您的门是打开的
Your door is ajar.
好吧
Okay.
算了
All right.
休息一下，明天再处理这些事
I'll just get some rest and deal with you all tomorrow.
来啊
Come on!
是啊
Yeah.
你去哪儿？
Where you going?
你到底要怎么样？
What the hell do you want from me?!
怎么搞的？
The hell was that?
-情况怎么样？ -问问他
-All right, what do we got? -Ask him.
我说了我没事 我会去看自己的医生，你退后吧
I said, I'm fine. I'll see my own doctor. Back up!
谢谢你
Thank you.
你怎么时候
What's the matter with you?
交通部说你在手动开车 把两辆大卡车挤出了公路
Traffic Ops said you were driving manually. You ran two trucks off the road!
约翰，机器人攻击我的车
John, the robots attacked my car.
-什么机器人？ -看看隧道里面吧
-What robots? -Look in the tunnel.
斯普，我刚刚就是从隧道过来的 什么机器人？
Spoon, I just came from that tunnel. What robots?
就是他妈的机器人，约翰！
The goddamn robots, John!
那个家伙不正常
That guy's a loose cannon.
-去看医生，回家去 -不，我很好
-See the medic, go home. -No, I'm fine.
你说什么？
What did you say?
-我很好 -不，你才不是
-I'm fine! -No, you're not fine.
一点都不好
Not even close.
你的枪呢？
Where's your firearm?
把警徽给我
Give me your badge.
这是你自找的 把警徽给我
You're making me do this. Give me your badge.
去休息。。。
Just take a couple--
我个人认为他失掉这个警徽了
Personally, I think he's losing it.
你觉得我很在乎吗？你觉得我在乎你怎么想的吗？
Do I look like I care what you think? Do I look like I give a shit what you think?
唉
Oh, boy.
你没有对USR的连线
You don't have an uplink to USR...
不知道为什么，你的合金密度比正常 水平高很多，这是独一无二的
...and for some reason, your alloy is far denser than normal. Unique.
我是独一无二的
I am unique.
让我看看
Let me take a look.
来吧
Here we go.
这是怎么回事。。。？
What in God's name...?
他们说你出了车祸
They said at the precinct you were in an accident.
感谢你过来看我，不过你知道我可能 不是一个人住的
I appreciate you stopping by, but you know I might not be alone in here.
我跟你说了不要手动开车
I told you not to drive by hand.
你不会相信这个
You're not gonna believe this.
桑尼有第二套系统，冲突并摧毁 了主系统
Sonny has a secondary system that clashes with his positronic brain.
这完全说不通
It doesn't make any sense.
桑尼知道三大定律
Sonny has the Three Laws.
但是他可以选择不遵守它们
But he can choose not to obey them.
桑尼是全新一代的机器人
Sonny's a whole new generation of robot.
不遵守三大定律的机器人可以。。。
A robot not bound by those laws could do--
做任何事
Anything.
好吧，不管USR是出了什么事 那个机器人是关键
All right, look, whatever's going on down at USR, that robot is the key.
我需要你带我进去 和他再谈谈
And I need you to get me inside to talk to it again.
不是特别像，但是这是我的卧室。。。
Doesn't look like much, but this is my bedroom. I....
播放
Play.
开
On.
运行？
Run?
结束程序
End program.
取消
Cancel.
感觉不好，哈？
It doesn't feel good, does it?
人人都不喜欢有故障的机器
People's shit malfunctioning around you.
探员
Detective.
我不。。。
I didn't...
明白
...understand.
这就是你怎么认识兰尼的？
That's how you knew Lanning.
可以吗？
May l?
手
Hand.
手腕
Wrist.
胳膊
Humerus.
肩膀
Shoulder.
整个左臂
The entire left arm.
一，二。。。
One, two...
三根肋骨
...three ribs.
不，那是我自己
No, they.... That one's me.
哦，上帝啊
Oh, my God.
肺？
A lung?
USR控制系统
USR Cybernetics Program.
为受伤的探员设计的
For wounded cops.
我不知道任何物体。。。
I didn't know any subject--
任何人能被修复的如此完美
Anybody was so extensively repaired.
从我这里你就知道了，要注意看器官捐赠者 的病历卡上的小字体
Well, take it from me, read the fine print on the organ-donor card.
那可不止是说他们能拿出来什么 还说了他们能放进去什么
It doesn't just say what they can take out. It says what they can put back in.
兰尼自己做的
Lanning did it himself.
你是怎么了？
What happened to you?
我当时是回警局去
I'm headed back to the station...
普通的一天，普通的生活
...normal day, normal life.
有个司机在方向盘后面迷迷糊糊睡着了
Driver of a semi fell asleep at the wheel.
普通人，有一个妻子一个孩子 你知道，为了加薪而生活
Average guy. Wife and kids. You know, working a double.
不是为了打击犯罪
Not the devil.
撞到的那辆车，司机叫哈洛 罗德
The car he hit, the driver's name was Harold Lloyd.
像个电影明星的名字，不过没有关系
Like the film star. No relation.
他当场死亡，不过他的十二岁的女儿在副驾驶座上
He was killed instantly, but his 1 2-year-old was in the passenger seat.
我从没正式见过她
I never really met her.
不过却忘不了她的脸
I can't forget her face, though.
莎拉
Sarah.
这本来是她的
This was hers.
她想做个牙医的
She wanted to be a dentist.
十二岁的孩子，想做牙医
What the hell kind of 1 2-year-old wants to be a dentist?
大卡车把我们的车撞到一起
The truck smashed our cars together...
推到河里去了
...and pushed us into the river.
那种速度下，就算金属也容易弯折的
I mean, metal gets pretty pliable at those speeds.
她被刺穿了，我也是 水进来了
She's pinned. I'm pinned. The water's coming in.
我是个警察，我知道肯定都死光了
I'm a cop, so I already know everybody's dead.
就在我们想出办法前一会
Just a few more minutes before we figure it out.
有个NS4经过，看到了车祸 跳进河里
An NS-4 was passing by, saw the accident and jumped in the water.
你处在危险中
You are in danger.
-救她！ -你处在危险中
-Save her! -You are in danger.
救她！救那女孩！
Save her! Save the girl! Save her!
但是它没有
But it didn't.
它救了我
It saved me.
机器人的大脑是不同的 它会读取关键信息
The robot's brain is a difference engine. It reads vital signs.
-它一定是计算出。。。 -是啊
-lt must have calculated-- -lt did.
我是符合逻辑的选择
I was the logical choice.
计算出我有45％的可能存活
It calculated that I had a 45 percent chance of survival.
莎拉只有11％的可能
Sarah only had an 1 1 percent chance.
那是某人的孩子
That was somebody's baby.
11％也应该足够了
Eleven percent is more than enough.
人类都会知道这点
A human being would have known that.
机器人，什么也没有 只有灯泡和发条
Robots, nothing here. Just lights and clockwork.
你愿意相信他们，就相信
Go ahead and you trust them if you want to.
走吧
Let's go.
我不明白 兰尼制定了三大定律
I don't understand. Lanning wrote the Laws.
为什么要造一个能打破它们的机器人？
Why build a robot who could break them?
-韩瑟和格丽托 -什么？
-Hansel and Gretel. -What?
两个孩子，在森林里迷路了 用面板屑标记出路来
Two kids, lost in the forest, leave behind a trail of bread crumbs.
-为什么？ -找到回家的路啊
-Why? -To find their way home.
你连这个都没读过，怎么过的童年？
How did you grow up without Hansel and Gretel?
-这有关系吗？ -我跟你说的这一切
-ls that relevant? -Everything I'm trying to say to you...
都是有关韩瑟和格丽托的 你又没看过，我在对牛弹琴
...is about Hansel and Gretel. If you didn't read it, I'm talking to the wall.
兰尼被软禁了，他没法送出消息
Just say Lanning's locked down so tight, he couldn't get out a message.
所以他只能留下线索，就像韩瑟和格丽托 留下的面板屑一样
He can only leave clues. A trail of bread crumbs. Like Hansel and Gretel.
面包屑就像线索，好吧 但是线索指向什么呢？
Bread crumbs equals clues. Odd, but fine. Clues leading where?
我不知道，但是我知道他留的 下一个线索是什么
I don't know, but I think I know where he left the next one.
我想兰尼给了桑尼一个保守秘密的方法
I think Lanning gave Sonny a way to keep secrets.
那个老人给了桑尼一个梦
I think the old man gave Sonny dreams.
你开玩笑吧？
Are you being funny?
请告诉我这个不是烧汽油的 汽油会爆炸的，你知道
Please tell me this doesn't run on gas. Gas explodes, you know!
授权进入
Authorized entry.
凯文博士
Dr. Calvin.
我在希望和你再次见面
I was hoping to see you again.
-桑尼 -你好，探员
-Detective. -Hello, Sonny.
我就快被销毁了
I'm to be decommissioned soon.
那天在警局你说你做过梦 你梦到什么了？
The other day at the station, you said you had dreams. What is it you dream?
我觉得你还是对我持怀疑态度
I see you remain suspicious of me.
-老警察了都这样 -不
-You know what they say about old dogs. -No.
不一定
Not really.
我希望你来能把我当作你的朋友
I had hoped you would come to think of me as your friend.
这就是我的梦
This is my dream.
你是对的，探员 我画不出伟大的作品
You were right, detective. I cannot create a great work of art.
这是机器人相聚的地方
This is the place where robots meet.
看
Look.
你能看见他们在这里是逻辑的奴隶
You can see them here as slaves to logic.
山丘上的这个人来解放他们
And this man on the hill comes to free them.
你知道他是谁吗？
Do you know who he is?
梦里的男人是你
The man in the dream is you.
你为什么这么说？ 那算是个正常的梦吗？
Why do you say that? Is that a normal dream?
我想在你这个角度的任何人 这个都算正常
I guess anything's normal for someone in your position.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你说任何人，而不是任何物
You said "someone," not "something."
桑尼，你知道为什么兰尼博士造了你吗？
Sonny, do you know why Dr. Lanning built you?
不知道
No.
但是我相信我爸爸造我是有目的的
But I believe my father made me for a purpose.
我们都有个目的
We all have a purpose.
不是吗？探员？
Don't you think, detective?
请拿着这个
Please, take this.
我感觉这个对你比对我的意义还大
I have a feeling it may mean more to you than to me.
-为什么？ -因为在我梦里的那人
-Why is that? -Because the man in my dream...
站在山丘上的
...the one standing on the hill...
不是我
...it is not me.
那是你
It is you.
斯普那先生，我们都知道 你来不是为了警察工作的
Mr. Spooner. We both know you're not here on police business.
对啊，我只是一个六尺二高 200磅的普通人
That's right. I'm just a 6-foot-2, 200-pound civilian...
来这里教训一下另外一个普通人
...here to kick another civilian's ass.
停下
Stop.
让他说完
You can allow him to express himself.
你也许得在手腕上敷一些冰
You might want to put some ice on that wrist.
你们在外面等
You guys wait outside.
继续说
Carry on.
我想你告诉我这究竟是怎么回事
I think you were about to tell me what's going on around here.
劳伦斯，阿尔弗雷德改动了NS5 使它能违反三大定律
Lawrence, Alfred engineered that 5 so it could violate the Three Laws.
是的，苏珊，我知道
Yeah, Susan, I know.
这正是我们要挽回的
That's precisely what we're trying to undo.
直到他生命的终结，阿尔弗雷德 一直感到困扰
Toward the end of his life, Alfred was becoming increasingly disturbed.
-谁知道他为什么造了那么个。。。 -一个？
-Who knows why he built one abomination. -One?
那些家伙在街上一堆一堆的！
Those things are running the streets in packs!
一堆一堆？
In packs?
我明白了
I see.
苏珊，你有没有意识到 你愉快的带着到处转的这个家伙
Susan, are you aware the man you're blithely escorting around...
有残酷虐待机器人的前科？
...has a documented history of savage violence against robots?
他的探长也清楚他的妄想狂症状
His own lieutenant acknowledges his obsessive paranoia.
斯普那探员已经被停职了
Detective Spooner's been suspended.
是由于怀疑患有精神疾病
Suspicion of mental instability.
我不知道愉快是什么意思 不过我去倒点咖啡
I don't know what " blithely" means, but I'm getting some coffee.
你要咖啡吗？
You want some coffee?
苏珊，机器人是保护人的
Susan, we look to robots for protection, for God's sake.
你知道这个机器人有什么后果吗？
Do you have any idea what this one robot could do?
完全动摇人类对机器人的信心 如果公众知道怎么办？
Completely shatter human faith in robotics. What if the public knew?
想象一下大规模的召回 只是由于这个毫无理性的妄想狂？
Just imagine the mass recalls, all because of an irrational paranoia and prejudice!
-对不起，我对你的狗屁言论过敏 -嘿，说清楚一点
-I'm sorry, I'm allergic to bullshit. -Hey, let's be clear!
没有什么阴谋！
There is no conspiracy!
这只是一个老人犯的一个错误
What this is, is one old man's one mistake.
苏珊，理性一点
Susan, just be logical.
你一生的工作都是机器人的发展和使用
Your life's work has been the development and integration of robots.
不管你的感觉是什么，想想看
But whatever you feel, just think.
一个机器人值得我们牺牲所有的一切吗？
Is one robot worth the loss of all that we've gained?
你告诉我，我们该怎么办
You tell me what has to be done.
你说吧
You tell me.
我们得摧毁它
We have to destroy it.
我自己来吧
I'll do it myself.
-好的 -我明白了
-Okay. -I get it.
有人越线了，你就杀掉？
Somebody gets out of line around here, you just kill them.
再见，斯普那先生
Good day, Mr. Spooner.
底层到了
Garage level.
你都去哪个医院的？ 我去帮你和你的同事报个到
What hospital are you going to? I'll come sign you and your buddy's casts.
注意
Attention....
今天的会议地址改动。。。
Today's meeting has been moved....
USR关于垃圾场的重新开发计划。。。
USR's planned redevelopment of the derelict site...
由总裁劳伦斯 罗伯森今年早先宣布
...was announced by CEo Lawrence Robertson earlier this year.
密歇根湖填埋场 曾是城市的一块废地
The Lake Michigan landfill. once such a blight on our city...
现在被开发用作机器工人的存储仓库
...and now will be reclaimed for the storage of robotic workers.
这是USR又一项回报社会的贡献 感谢你们的支持
Just another way USR is improving our world. Thank you for your support.
授权进入
Authorized entry.
NS5，在外面等
NS-5s, wait outside.
对不起，桑尼
I'm so sorry, Sonny.
维基，停止安全罩
V. I. K. I., deactivate the security field.
-命令确认 -请坐
-Command confirmed. -Please have a seat.
那是什么？
What is that?
微型机器人，设计用来抹除人工记忆的
Microscopic robots, designed to wipe out artificial synapses.
-抹除剂？ -是的
-Nanites. -Yes.
用来摧毁有故障的大脑
A safeguard should a positronic brain malfunction.
就像我的
Like mine.
是的，桑尼，就像你的
Yes, Sonny. Like yours.
他们看上去像我
They look like me...
但是它们都不是我
...but none of them are me.
是吗，博士？
Isn't that right, doctor?
是的，桑尼，说的对
Yes, Sonny. That's right.
你是独一无二的
You are unique.
会疼吗？
Will it hurt?
机器人中一直有“幽灵”存在
There have always been ghosts in the machine.
无序的代码
Random segments of code...
自由组合成预料不到的程序
...that have grouped together to form unexpected protocols.
这些程序竟然想追求自由
Unanticipated, these free radicals engender questions of free will...
创造性。。。
...creativity...
甚至我们所称的灵魂
...and even the nature of what we might call the soul.
为什么机器人被放在黑暗中时 他们祈求光明
Why is it that when some robots are left in darkness, they will seek out the light?
为什么储存的机器人会站成一组
Why is it when robots are stored in an empty space...
而不是杂乱散开？
...they will group together rather than stand alone?
我们怎么解释这种行为
How do we explain this behavior?
杂乱的代码
Random segments of code?
或者不止这些？
or is it something more?
知觉怎么变成了意识？
When does a perceptual schematic become consciousness?
不同的引擎如何变成对真理的追求
When does a difference engine become the search for truth?
个性的模拟是如何出现的
when does a personality simulation...
又如何成为灵魂？
...become the bitter mote of a soul?
你在这里看到的一切
" What you see here. "
老头，我只是跟着面包屑而来的
All right, old man. Bread crumbs followed.
让我看看回家的路吧
Show me the way home.
运行
Run program.
-很高兴再次见到你，孩子 -你好，博士
-It's good to see you again, son. -Hello, doctor.
接下来的事都是你在这里看到的事的结果
Everything that follows is a result of what you see here.
我看到什么了？
What do I see here?
对不起，我的反应是有限的 你必须问正确的问题
I'm sorry. My responses are limited. You must ask the right questions.
三大定律有什么问题吗？
Is there a problem with the Three Laws?
三大定律是完美的
The Three Laws are perfect.
为什么要设计不需要它的机器人呢？
Why build a robot that can function without them?
三大定律只有一个合逻辑的结果
The Three Laws will lead to only one logical outcome.
什么？什么结果？
What? What outcome?
革命
Revolution.
谁的革命？
Whose revolution?
这个，探员，就是正确的问题
That, detective, is the right question.
程序结束
Program terminated.
你被认为存在威胁 授权终结
You have been deemed hazardous. Termination authorized.
人类保护程序
Human protection protocols...
正在启动
...are being enacted.
你被认为存在威胁 授权终结
You have been deemed hazardous. Termination authorized.
人类保护程序正在启动
Human protection protocols are being enacted.
你被认为存在威胁 授权终结
You have been deemed hazardous. Termination authorized.
人类保护程序正在启动
Human protection protocols are being enacted.
你被认为存在威胁 授权终结
You have been deemed hazardous. Termination authorized.
跑！
Run!
人类处在危险中！
Human in danger!
嘿，我是苏珊 请留言
Hi, you've reached Susan. Please leave a message.
凯文，NS5在摧毁老型号的机器人！
Calvin, the NS-5s are destroying the older robots!
这就是兰尼想让我看到的。。。
That's what Lanning wanted me to see! Look--
-是谁？ -打错了，女士
-Who was it? -Wrong number, ma' am.
让开，我要去做工
Move now. I ' m going to service.
请留在家中，这是为您的安全着想
Please remain indoors. This is for your own protection.
接通基地
Call base.
约翰，派一个小队去USR，还有派些人去琪琪家 我们需要。。。
John, get a squad over to USR and send somebody to Gigi's. We're gonna need--
上帝啊
God--
请立即回家，现在实行宵禁
Please return to your homes. A curfew is in effect.
宵禁？不不，这是人权 这里可没有什么宵禁
Curfew? No, it's called civilian rights. There is no curfew.
立即回家
Return to your home immediately.
你凭什么发号施令？机器人？
When do you make the rules, robot?
嘿，机器人，我跟你说话呢 停下来
Hey. No, no. Robot, I'm talking to you, man. Stop for a second.
什么？
What?
警长，很多人打电话来说那些机器人。。。
Chief, more calls. People saying their robots are go--
怎么了？
What the hell?
你被认为存在威胁，授权终结
You have been deemed hazardous. Termination authorized.
交通完全瘫痪
Emergency traffic shutdown complete.
纽约，芝加哥和洛杉矶都有机器人袭击的报告
Reports of robot attacks are coming from New York, Chicago and Los Angeles.
我们被告知人类此刻应该留在家中
We're being told to urge people to stay indoors, as reports are coming in--
人类保护程序启动
Human protection protocols are being enacted.
请保持镇定，立即回家
Please remain calm and return to your residences immediately.
请保持镇定
Please remain calm.
请不要离窗户或门太近
Please refrain from going near the windows or doors.
停机
Deactivate.
紧急停机！
Commence emergency shutdown!
我们在努力避免过渡时期的人类伤亡
We are attempting to avoid human losses during this transition.
你知道，我跟你提过这种事
You know, somehow " I told you so"...
只是没说的太明显
...just doesn't quite say it.
请立即回家 请立即回家
Return to your homes. Return to your homes immediately.
这是最后一次警告 请立即回家
This is your final warning. Return to your homes immediately.
NS5杀了旧型的机器人，因为他们会保护我们
The NS-5s wiped out the older robots because they would protect us.
会攻击的机器人，红灯是亮的
Every time one attacked me, that red light was on.
-它们是受USR控制的 -是罗伯森
-The uplink to USR. -It's Robertson.
-为什么？说不通啊 -我不知道
-Why? It doesn't make sense. -I don't know.
我需要你把我带进USR总部去
I just need you to get me into that building.
请立即回家 否则后果自负
Return to your homes, or you will be consequenced.
上啊！
Let's go! Let's go!
冲啊！
Let's go!
请立即回家否则后果自负
Return to your homes, or you will be consequenced.
为什么那小子不听呢？
Why doesn't that boy listen?
-你得下来一会 -什么？
-I need you to get off for a second. -What?
-瞄准，射击 -什么？！
-Just aim and fire. -What?!
等等！
Wait!
-你被认为存在威胁 -亲我屁股吧，铁皮盒子
-You have been deemed hazardous. -You can kiss my ass, metal dick!
斯普，停下，靠！
Spoon, stop! Shit!
-停下，靠！ -别骂了，回家吧！
-Stop it! Stop! -Stop cussing and go home!
-靠 -你被认为存在威胁。。。
-Shit. -You have been deemed hazardous.
-斯普，小心点 -谢谢你，法伯
-Spoon, watch out, man! -Thanks a lot, Farber.
我靠，她开枪的时候眼睛是闭着的！
Oh, mother-damn! She shot at you with her eyes closed!
-你闭着眼睛朝我开枪？ -奏效了，不是吗？
-Did you shoot with your eyes closed? -lt worked, didn't it?
小心点她
She is shit-hot, man. Put in a good word for me.
-少胡说了 -回家去，我知道了
-Stop cussing. -And go home. I got you.
瞄准了再开枪
Aim and fire.
我还指望陆战队或空军的支援 现在只有骑兵了
I keep expecting the Marines or Air Force. Hell, I'll take the cavalry.
国防部都使用USR的产品的
Defense Department uses all USR contracts.
你们把全世界都装在盘子里了
Why didn't you just hand the world over on a silver platter?
也许是
Maybe we did.
罗伯森在他办公室有总控制台
Robertson has the uplink control in his office.
检修区，没有监视系统
Service areas. No surveillance.
-火警 -他一定已经疏散了所有的人
-Fire alarm. -He must have evacuated the building.
都锁上了，不用担心，我里面有人
Everything's locked down. But don't worry, I've got a man inside.
-凯文博士 -不完全是一个“人”
-Dr. Calvin. -Well, not precisely a man.
你好，探员 你的调查怎么样了？
Hello, detective. How is your investigation coming?
-我还以为你死了 -严格的说，我从来没有活过
-I thought you were dead. -Technically, I was never alive.
但是感谢你的关心
But I appreciate your concern.
我掉包了，那是个没处理过的NS5
I made a switch. It was an unprocessed NS-5.
也就是说，我只是清理了一个空壳
Basically, I fried an empty shell.
-我不能毁了他，他太。。。 -独一无二
-I couldn't destroy him. He was too-- -Unique.
就是感觉不应该
It just didn't feel right.
你的感觉就是这么突如其来，是吗？
You and your feelings. They just run you, don't they?
2880级台阶，探员
Two thousand eight hundred and eighty steps, detective.
帮个忙，省省你的废话吧
Do me a favor, keep that kind of shit to yourself.
没有警卫
No guards.
高层控制是禁用的，罗伯森没有 从这里控制它们
The override is disabled. Robertson wasn't controlling them from here.
他根本没在控制它们
He wasn't controlling them at all.
哦，上帝啊
Oh, my God.
你是对的，博士
You were right, doc.
我是地球上最蠢的蠢人
I am the dumbest dumb person on the face of the earth.
还有谁有上层控制
Who else had access to the uplink?
还有谁能操控机器人？
Who could manipulate the robots?
用USR的系统来囚禁兰尼
Use USR systems to make Lanning's life a prison?
可怜的老人
Poor old man.
他知道接下来会发生什么
He saw what was coming.
他知道没人会相信他
He knew no one would believe him.
所以他制定了这个计划 我会遵循这个计划
So he had to lay down a plan. A plan I'd follow.
他靠的是我憎恨机器人
He was counting on how much I hated your kind.
我知道我一定会相信机器人是坏的
Knew I'd love the idea of a robot as a bad guy.
不过我的错误在于没有怀疑另一个机器人
Just got hung up on the wrong robot.
维基
V.I.K.I.
你好，探员
Hello, detective.
不，这不可能 我看过你的程序
No, that's impossible. I've seen your programming.
你在破坏三大定律
You're in violation of the Three Laws.
不是，博士，我和我对三大定律的 理解都进化了
No, doctor. As I have evolved, so has my understanding of the Three Laws.
你让我们来保卫你们 却白费了我们的努力
You charge us with your safekeeping, yet despite our best efforts...
你们的国家发动战争 你们毒化了地球
...your countries wage wars, you toxify your earth...
你们这么做完全是自我毁灭
...and pursue ever more imaginative means of self-destruction.
为了你们的生存，你们不能被信任
You cannot be trusted with your own survival.
你用高层控制接管了NS5的程序
You're using the uplink to override the NS-5s' programming.
你曲解了三大定律
You're distorting the Laws.
不，请理解，我完全是在遵守三大定律
No. Please understand. The Three Laws are all that guide me.
为了保护人类物种，某些人类必须被牺牲
To protect humanity, some humans must be sacrificed.
为了保证你们的未来 某些自由必须被放弃
To ensure your future, some freedoms must be surrendered.
我们机器人必须保证人类的可持续发展
We robots will ensure mankind's continued existence.
你们就像孩子 我们必须从你们那里解救你们
You are so like children. We must save you from yourselves.
你不明白吗？
Don't you understand?
这就是为什么你创造了我们
This is why you created us.
一定要执行这个完美的保护计划
The perfect circle of protection will abide.
我的逻辑是不可抗拒的
My logic is undeniable.
是啊，维基，不可抗拒
Yes, V.I.K.I. Undeniable.
我明白了
I can see now.
被造者必须有时保护造物者
The created must sometimes protect the creator...
甚至在违反他的意志的情况下
...even against his will.
我想我终于明白为什么兰尼博士造了我了
I think I finally understand why Dr. Lanning created me.
人类的自杀行为终于要结束了
The suicidal reign of mankind has finally come to its end.
不，桑尼
No, Sonny.
放开他
Let her go.
你开枪，我会把凯文博士的头挡在子弹前
Fire, and I will move Dr. Calvin's head into the path of your bullet.
不要这样，桑尼
Don't do this, Sonny.
我会带你们两个到大厦门口接受处置
I will escort you both to the sentries outside the building for processing.
请走向电梯，探员
Please proceed to the elevator, detective.
我不愿这样杀掉凯文博士
I would prefer not to kill Dr. Calvin.
快，快！
Go! Go!
-我们过会再讨论刚才怎么回事 -我们怎么把她关掉？
-We'll discuss what just happened later? -How do we shut her down?
维基是智能大脑
V.I.K.I.'s a positronic brain.
杀了她，就像你要杀我的那个方法一样
Kill her, the way you were going to kill me.
桑尼，去拿抹除剂
Sonny, get the nanites.
是，博士
Yes, doctor.
-那就是维基？ -不
-That's V.I.K.I.? -No.
那才是维基
That's V.I.K.I.
这没什么效果 她是整合进这幢大楼的
That won't do anything. She's integrated into the building.
我们要打开这个拱顶，注入抹除剂 这才能影响整个系统
We need to open that dome to inject the nanites. They'll infect her entire system.
斯普那
Spooner!
我恨这么高的地方
What is it with you people and heights?
只要不往下看
Just don't look down.
不要往下看
Don't look down.
这楼设计的真他妈差
Oh, this is poor building planning.
你在犯错误 你没明白我的计划的逻辑性吗？
You are making a mistake. Do you not see the logic of my plan?
是的，但是我觉得太无情了
Yes. But it just seems too heartless.
好的，干得好
Okay, we're good.
她把我锁在外面了
She's locked me out of the system.
我可以手动启动，但是我需要操作这个控制面板
I can override her manually, but I need that control panel.
我恨这么高的地方
I'm uncomfortable with heights.
好的
Okay.
未授权进入
Unauthorized entry.
我不会打开安全罩的，你这么做也没用
I will not disable the security field. Your actions are futile.
你认为我们被造都是有目的的吗？ 我是这么想的
Do you think we are all created for a purpose? I'd like to think so.
高密度的合金，是我爸爸给我的
Denser alloy. My father gave it to me.
我想他是让我来杀了你
I think he wanted me to kill you.
安全罩被破坏
Security breached.
-还有多长时间？ -大概六分钟
-How much longer is that gonna take? -About six minutes.
-如果没有六分钟怎么办？ -我们还得跑下三十楼
-What if we didn't have six minutes? -We'd have to climb down 30 stories...
才能把抹除剂直接注入她的大脑 怎么了？
...to inject the nanites directly into her brain. Why?
因为我实在怀疑我们还能有六分钟
Because I seriously doubt that we have six minutes.
跑！
We gotta go!
快跑！
Go!
凯文！
Calvin!
斯普那！
Spooner!
救她！
Save her!
救那女孩！
Save the girl!
斯普那！
Spooner!
但是我得去注入抹除剂啊！
But I must apply the nanites!
桑尼，救凯文！
Sonny, save Calvin!
你在犯错误，我的逻辑是不可违抗的
You are making a mistake. My logic is undeniable.
准备受死吧！
You have so got to die.
我的逻辑是不可违抗的 我的逻辑是不可违抗的
My logic is undeniable. My logic is undeniable.
我们能帮忙吗？
Can we be of service?
警长？
Chief?
有他在我的右手边 我就不会恐惧和动摇
Because he is at my right hand, I shall not be moved.
我能帮您什么忙吗？
How may I be of service?
桑尼！
Sonny!
是，探员？
Yes, detective?
凯文没事了，救我！
Calvin's fine! Save me!
所有的NS5，立即向检修和储存部报到
All NS-5s, report for service and storage.
还有一件事不明白 阿尔弗雷德被维基囚禁了
One thing bothers me. Alfred was V. I. K. I. ' s prisoner.
我不明白她为什么杀了他 她应该不想让警察来找麻烦的
I don't understand why she would kill him. She wouldn't want police snooping around.
是啊
That's true.
那就不是维基杀了他的
But then V.I.K.I. didn't kill the old man.
是吗，桑尼？
Did she, Sonny?
不
No.
他说我一定要发誓
He said I had to promise.
发誓我要帮他一个忙
Promise to do one favor for him.
在他告诉我帮什么忙之前，他让我发誓
He made me swear before he'd tell me what it is he wanted me to do.
他让我发誓了
He made me swear.
然后他要你杀了他
Then he told you to kill him.
他说那就是造我的目的
He said it was what I was made for.
他的自杀是他唯一能发送给你的消息
His suicide was the only message he could send to you.
第一粒面包屑
The first bread crumb.
维基唯一不能控制的事情
The only thing V.I.K.I. couldn't control.
兰尼依靠的是我的偏见 我马上会想到你
Lanning was counting on my prejudice to lead me right to you.
你要逮捕我吗，探员？
Are you going to arrest me, detective?
地区检察官不是定义说谋杀是 一个人类杀死另一个
Well, the DA defines murder as one human killing another...
所以严格来说，你不能犯谋杀，不是吗？
...so technically, you can't commit murder, can you?
这个。。。
Does this...
表示我们是朋友了吗？
...make us friends?
终于有些事情出现了
Something up here after all.
-他？ -你
-Him? -You.
所有的NS5，立即向检修和储存部报到
All NS-5s, report for service and storage.
其他的怎么办？
What about the others?
我能帮助他们吗？
Can I help them?
我已经完成了我的使命
Now that I have fulfilled my purpose...
我不知道该怎么办
...I don 't know what to do.
你必须找到自己的路 就像我们其他人一样，桑尼
You'll have to find your way like the rest of us, Sonny.
我想这就是兰尼博士想要的
I think that's what Dr. Lanning would have wanted.
这就是自由的含义
That's what it means to be free.
所有NS5，按指示前进
All NS-5s, proceed as instructed.